<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Before | From House to Home]]></title>
  <link href="http://allenar.github.io/blog/categories/before/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://allenar.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-11T07:57:34+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://allenar.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alex Allen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Reveal Part 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://allenar.github.io/blog/2014/11/04/the-reveal-part-2/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-04T21:37:50+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://allenar.github.io/blog/2014/11/04/the-reveal-part-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Upstairs</h1>

<p>Three weeks ago I gave you the downstairs reveal and since then I&rsquo;ve been farily busy in at the house getting on with things but I thought it finally time I get on and do the upstairs and garden reveal.</p>

<h2><strong>Floor Plan</strong></h2>

<p><img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/Floorplan.JPG" title="Floor Plan" alt="alt text" /></p>

<p>For those of you with a poor memory or who have been lucky enough to stumble across this blog for the first time, the above picture shows the layout for our house.</p>

<h2><strong>Master Bedroom</strong></h2>

<p><img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_12.JPG" title="Fireplace" alt="alt text" />
<img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_13.JPG" title="Doorway" alt="alt text" /></p>

<p>In terms of colour, this is the room that has been painted in the most neutral colour of all rooms in the house. It&rsquo;s actually in a pretty good condition decor-wise the only real issue with this room, like the rest of the house, is that the window boxes and windows themselves just don&rsquo;t fit the holes.
So although it might look pretty good, it is definitely going to be very cold as we move into the Winter. Also, like in a lot of houses of this age the fireplace has been boarded up. Fingers crossed that when we get around to opening it up that the original is just sat behind there waiting for us.</p>

<h2><strong>Bedroom 2</strong></h2>

<p><img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_14.JPG" title="Fireplace" alt="alt text" />
<img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_15.JPG" title="Corner" alt="alt text" /></p>

<p>Another fairly reasonable room in terms of decor. The fireplace is in tact and the colours aren&rsquo;t overly offensive, so long as you can look past the mountain of blu-tac attached to the wall when it was clearly some sort of poster montage! In the corner you can see again where they have failed to decorate behind furniture and also where tracking has been used to put up shelves. Delightful.</p>

<h2><strong>Bedroom 3</strong></h2>

<p><img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_16.JPG" title="Window" alt="alt text" />
<img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_17.JPG" title="Fireplace" alt="alt text" /></p>

<p>More signs of the green colour in this room. Not only that, but you can see the third and finally radiator in the entire house&hellip; it&rsquo;s just a shame that this one isn&rsquo;t actually plumbed in! On the plus side there&rsquo;s another original fireplace and just plenty of potential.</p>

<h2><strong>Bathroom</strong></h2>

<p><img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_18.JPG" title="Toilet" alt="alt text" />
<img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_19.JPG" title="Bath" alt="alt text" /></p>

<p>Functional. That&rsquo;s about the only way I can describe this room without being rude.</p>

<p>The colour isn&rsquo;t great, the suite is worse and it doesn&rsquo;t come out in the picture very well but if you are lying in the bath with your head at the tap end you actually have the airing cupboard built over your head. Combine that with the header tank offshot just sat on a couple of brackets I&rsquo;d be very nervous about actually using this bath for any period of time.</p>

<h2><strong>Garden</strong></h2>

<p><img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_20.JPG" title="Garden View" alt="alt text" />
<img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_21.JPG" title="Overgrown" alt="alt text" /></p>

<p>And finally here are a couple of shots of the garden. It&rsquo;s really hard to tell from the pictures but there is actually quite a bit of space out there. If we look over into the neighbours we can see just how much because the dimensions are almost identical it&rsquo;s just a combination of the overgrown borders and the bush at the end of the garden. You may be saying to yourself &ldquo;bush&rdquo;, and yes it is actually a bush.
That Laurel bush may be about 30ft tall and have a diameter of more than our garden but yes it is actually just a bush. I&rsquo;m not looking forward to having to remove that, especially as we have no rear / side access so disposal is going to be a challenge.</p>

<p>So that&rsquo;s it, you&rsquo;ve seen everything our house has to offer. Where would you start? How long do you think it&rsquo;s going to be before we can comfortably move in?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Reveal]]></title>
    <link href="http://allenar.github.io/blog/2014/10/11/the-reveal/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-11T11:24:41+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://allenar.github.io/blog/2014/10/11/the-reveal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Before</h1>

<p>So with all the best intentions in the world it turns out that we haven&rsquo;t taken the best before photos. I blame it on a combination of the excitement of getting the keys, it being dark when we first walked through and only having an iPhone to take photos with. Anyway, you can still get some ideas as to the challenges that face us over the coming months, or should that be years?!</p>

<h2><strong>Floor Plan</strong></h2>

<p><img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/Floorplan.JPG" title="Floor Plan" alt="alt text" /></p>

<p>So above is the floor plan for our new house. The problem with having plenty of space / rooms in a situation like this is it means that there is plenty to actually have to put right in the first place. We definitely went into this with the long-term in mind; let&rsquo;s just hope that the long-term doesn&rsquo;t take that long to become the reality.</p>

<h2><strong>Hallway</strong></h2>

<p><img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_01.JPG" title="Into the hallway" alt="alt text" />
<img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_02.JPG" title="The porch" alt="alt text" /></p>

<p>This is the first thing you see when you open the front door, it&rsquo;s a lovely shade of baby pink isn&rsquo;t it?! Not only is the colour not to our taste but the wallpaper is actually woodchip too. That&rsquo;s going to be fun to remove. On the plus side the original entrance porch tiles are there and are all still in tact; albeit in need of a good cleaning up.</p>

<h2><strong>Sitting Room</strong></h2>

<p><img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_03.JPG" title="Sitting room - fireplace" alt="alt text" />
<img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_04.JPG" title="Sitting room - window bay" alt="alt text" /></p>

<p>The sitting room is a great size and proportion with some fantastic original wooden sash windows in the bay. It also comes with a few not so welcome features: the awful 1970&rsquo;s (at a guess) fireplace, the damp under the windows and the surface-mount plug socket. The sockets are a theme throughout the house, but sometimes it can be difficult to spot them as some rooms only have a single socket!</p>

<h2><strong>Dining Room</strong></h2>

<p><img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_05.JPG" title="Dining room 1" alt="alt text" />
<img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_06.JPG" title="Dining room 2" alt="alt text" />
<img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_07.JPG" title="Dining room 3" alt="alt text" /></p>

<p>This is probably the most colourful room in the house. Not by design, but more because the previous owners clearly never felt the need to move furniture when they decided to redecorate. It doesn&rsquo;t come across in the pictures but there are actually four different colours on the walls in here. The &ldquo;top colour&rdquo; is meant to be the green, but it&rsquo;s not just any green, it&rsquo;s a green that would be best described as fire exit green. Lovely!</p>

<p>Again there&rsquo;s more damp to contend with in this room and a lot of built-in shelving that won&rsquo;t be lasting very long at all.</p>

<h2><strong>Rear Reception Room</strong></h2>

<p><img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_08.JPG" title="Rear reception" alt="alt text" />
<img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_09.JPG" title="Under the stairs" alt="alt text" /></p>

<p>More pink, more surface-mount sockets and this time there&rsquo;s a back boiler and gas fireplace to add to the mix. It does have this cute (perhaps not?) under stairs storage cupboard that may come in handy when the wife won&rsquo;t leave me alone.</p>

<h2><strong>Kitchen</strong></h2>

<p><img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_10.JPG" title="Kitchen left" alt="alt text" />
<img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_11.JPG" title="Kitchen right" alt="alt text" /></p>

<p>Somebody once said something about having enough room to swing a cat. I don&rsquo;t think either of ours would appreciate it if I tried in here as they would definitely hit the cupboards and wall on both sides. Small would be the understatement of the century!</p>

<h2><strong>Garden Room / WC</strong></h2>

<p><img src="https://allenar.github.com/images/IMG_11a.JPG" title="Garden room" alt="alt text" /></p>

<p>This is the only photo we appear to have taken of the garden room which is a shame as it&rsquo;s the only room, along with the downstairs WC, that have actually seen any redecorating in what feels like the last 50 years. It&rsquo;s just a shame that we haven&rsquo;t been given a key to the door.</p>

<p>So that&rsquo;s it for the first instalment of the new house reveal. The upstairs and garden will be featured in the next episode; we don&rsquo;t want to give you too much of a good thing in one go now do we??</p>

<p>So what&rsquo;s your favourite feature? What would you tackle first? Is there anything that you think might actually survive through to project completion?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
